# **Rubiyet** Fardous

# **Software Engineer**

+880 1862 297 140 rubiyetfardous@gmail.com

# rubiyet.me github.com/rubiyet

Ohaka, Bangladesh in linkedin.com/in/rubiyetfardous

### About Me

A Front-End Developer with deep knowledge of modern web technologies capable of designing and implementing visually pleasing, efficient, and optimized software. Experienced in delivering quality products in production environments following proper design principles and methodologies.

# Work Experience

#### Junior Software Engineer

HelloTask Pte. Ltd.

An app-based platform for hiring domestic workers, just like Uber.

December 2021 to Present (1 year+)

- Developed the Front-End of the Admin Panel with -
  - React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS
  - Apollo GraphQL, REST API
  - Vercel Hosting and Git Version Control
- Contribute to the design process by collaborating with designers using-
  - Figma
- Demo Live on: https://hellotask.vercel.app

#### Front End Web Developer

#### ReelBoard

A startup is working on connecting digital billboards to a centralized network for efficient and analyticsdriven content delivery.

August 2021 to November 2021 (4 months)

- Designed and developed Admin Panel Front-End and Landing pages. Tech-stack -
  - React (Next.js), Vue.js, Bootstrap 5
  - Apollo GraphQL
  - Vercel Hosting, GitHub Pages, Git Version Control
- Demo Live on: https://reelboard.vercel.app

#### Front End Web Developer

#### Retriko

An Independent client-focused developer group. January 2021 to July 2021 (7 months)

- Design and Develop Static Websites
- WordPress site Development
- Demo Live on: https://rubiyet.me/retriko-console

## Tech Stack

#### Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python, C/C++, JAVA, C#, SQL

#### Frameworks

React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, Nest.js, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Bulma

#### Protocol, Tools & Others

Apollo GraphQL, REST API, Redux, React Query, WordPress, Vercel, GitHub Pages, Git, Linux, Nginx.

# Education

#### BSc. in CSE

American International University-Bangladesh

# Year: 2018 - 2022 | CGPA: 3.32

### **Publication**

Applying Scrum Development on Safety Critical Systems

DOI: 10.5815/ijitcs.2022.05.04

# Personal Projects

#### ShoeMart

**Project Description** 

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Vercel Hosting
- Demo Live on: https://shoemart.vercel.app

#### **BdBookies**

**Project Description** 

- React (Next.js), Tailwind CSS, Redux, React Query, Firebase, Vercel Hosting.
- Demo Live on: https://gotogether.vercel.app

#### School Management System

**Project Description** 

- HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, MySQL.
- Github: https://github.com/rubiyet/School\_Portal